<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Barriers: The changing relationship between humans and the environment in Belize.</title>
    <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Barriers: The changing relationship between humans and the environment in Belize.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright UNC Hussman School of Journalism and Media</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://barriers.unc.edu/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coral in the Crossfire</title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/coral/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/coral/</guid>
      <description>Mordy Mis stands on the shore of Tom Owens Caye, a one-acre island halfway between Belize and Honduras. On a clear day he can see 25 miles, to the ridgeline of the Maya Mountains, some of Central America’s highest peaks. Most days, though, the 26-year-old is surrounded only by open ocean, silver and blue waves stretching endlessly in every direction.
In the tide pool at his feet, two nurse sharks, the Caribbean’s most docile predators, are circling the carcass of a lionfish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controversy on Deck</title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/tourism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/tourism/</guid>
      <description>It’s 6 a.m. in Monkey River, a village in southern Belize, and not many people are awake. The silence was flooding the place until the crow of the roosters and the sound of starting motors interrupted the stillness of the summer morning. The tour guides are getting their boats ready to go to Placencia, a tourist destination 40 minutes north of this small, quiet community.
They will pick up tourists and bring them back to Monkey River to do the same tour they’ve done for at least 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bittersweet</title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/culture/</guid>
      <description>Nestled inside the lush green forest off the coast of Belize, dozens of green and red cacao pods grow.
Cacao has been cultivated here since 1800 B.C., when the Mayans first discovered they could turn these pods into a rich drink.
The pods start out as white flowers, smaller than a pinky finger, pollinated by insects so tiny they can hardly be seen with the human eye. After more than three years, these flowers grow into oblong pods roughly the size of cantaloupes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tide to Trash</title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/waste/</guid>
      <description>Flies swarm at Vincent Budna’s feet as he walks through the piles of rusty paint cans, cardboard boxes and crumpled water bottles.
Smoke slowly wafts skyward from heat-induced trash fires at the edge of the gravel path, sending toxic fumes into the cloudless sky. A flock of vultures perches on a mound of fresh garbage, squawking eagerly as they feast on a moldy hunk of bread. A soft ocean breeze blows, and trash bags flutter in the wind, rippling across the 100-acre property in a wave of black, non-biodegradable plastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeding the Sea</title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/seaweed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/seaweed/</guid>
      <description>Lowell “Japs” Godfrey is the king of Little Water Caye.
The small island is 18 miles offshore from the Belizean village of Placencia, and mostly covered in shrubs. Only Godfrey, who boats out to the caye and stays for days or weeks at a time, and a few sea rangers, are here. He usually sleeps in a tent under the coconut trees he planted when he first came to the island several years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/generations/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/fishers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/fishers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/rooted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/rooted/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/elders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/elders/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/weeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/weeds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://barriers.unc.edu/beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://barriers.unc.edu/beauty/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>